Do you play spades?
Do you want to learn some different ways to play spades?
Hi, my name is Dean Hale, and I'm going to teach you a game called suicide spades.
The cards are dealt out in the same fashion as a normal spades game would be; thirteen cards for each player.
The difference in this game is you have to bid either nil or at least four tricks.
The first person, the first partnership would bid either nil or four.
The second person can bid the same.
They can bid the same as the, as their partner took, or they can make the other bid.
If I bid four and my partner also bids four they get to be the four and I have to be the nil, so you're going to be opposite what your partner does.
The other players are going to do the same thing.
If you get a successful nil bid that's worth a hundred points.
An unsuccessful nil bid is worth negative one hundred points.
Each time you get your trick you're going to be ten; if you called four it's ten times four.
You're going to get forty points.
If you don't make it you're going to get points deducted.
So, in suicide spades the thing is you're going to be having a nil bid in the hand each time, which is obviously going to put a lot of pressure on both teams.
You're going to play to an agreed upon score, and the first team to get that score wins.
My name is Dean Hale.
Enjoy your new form of spades, suicide spades.